Fighting, killing, maiming. Agent Orange and the
torture cages were the easy part!
Combat Shock is a horror, war, drama film directed by Buddy Giovinazzo.
A dangerously disturbed Vietnam veteran struggles with life 15 years after his return
home, and slowly falls into insanity from his gritty urban lifestyle.
Frankie Dunlan (as Ricky Giovinazzo), played by Rick Giovinazzo.
Cathy Dunlan, played by Veronica Stork.
Paco - Gang Leader, played by Mitch Maglio.
Labo - Gang Member, played by Asaph Livni.
Morbe - Gang Member, played by Nick Nasta.
Mike - Junkie, played by Michael Tierno.
Combat Shock is a 1986 exploitation war drama film written, produced, and directed by
Buddy Giovinazzo and starring his brother Rick Giovinazzo in the lead role.
The film was distributed by Troma Entertainment.
The plot of the film takes place in Staten Island, and follows an unemployed Vietnam veteran named Frankie Dunlan living in total
poverty with his nagging wife, his baby (who is deformed due to Frankie's exposure to Agent Orange), and junkie friends.
Unable to get a job and surrounded by the depravity of urban life
and crime, he begins to lose his grip on sanity.
The film received mixed to negative reviews upon its release, but
has since gained a cult following among Troma Fans.
The film explores themes of vietnam, post-traumatic stress
disorder (ptsd), nihilism, flashback, poverty.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.